Simrit Kaul

Ş simritkaul | in Simrit | ≥ kaulsimrit@gmail.com | +91982004889

About Me

I'm a software developer, known for my inquisitive nature, collaborative spirit, and methodical approach. I specialize in detailed work, focusing on controllable factors and driving improvements. My aim is to simplify complexities and innovate within my field by staying abreast of technological advancements.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Analyst - Deloitte USI

Sep 2022 - present

Bengaluru

- Developed UI components in **React Js** for an enterprise child welfare application serving a prominent US county.
- Implemented .NET Core 6 microservices, ensuring scalability and reliability of critical functionalities.
- Optimized system performance and maintained architectural integrity within a dynamic environment while collaborating with cross-functional teams to deliver user-centric solutions for complex business requirements.
- Received an **Applause Award** for my contribution in development of the first phase of the application in the year 2023.

Intern - Momenttext Jul 2022 - Aug 2022

Remote

 Utilized OpenCV and advanced deep learning techniques for diverse challenges, from precise image segmentation to seamlessly blending extracted human subjects into alternative backgrounds.

PROJECTS

Autophotoshop



Developed a project utilizing DeepLabV3+, MaskRCNN, and OpenCV technologies. This innovative solution enables precise segmentation of human subjects from images and seamless integration into alternative backgrounds, offering flexible positioning and resizing capabilities.

EDUCATION

2018 - 2022	B.Tech in ECE with Specialisation in IoT and Sensors at VIT, Vellore	(CGPA: 9.03/10)
2017 - 2018	Higher Secondary at DPS Bopal, Ahmedabad	(84.6%)
2015 - 2016	Matriculation at DPS Bonal, Ahmedahad	(CGPA: 10/10)

Publications

Sethi, Krish et al. (2021). "FaceLock Homes: A Contactless Smart Home Security System to Prevent COVID Transmission". In: 2021 Sixth International Conference on Wireless Communications, Signal Processing and Networking (WiSPNET), pp. 75–79. DOI: 10.1109/WiSPNET51692.2021.9419453.

Jindal, Sumit Kumar et al. (May 2022). "Efficient in-depth analysis and optimum design parameter estimation of MEMS capacitive pressure sensor utilizing analytical approach for square diaphragm". In: *Journal of Computational Electronics* 21.4, pp. 992–1004. DOI: 10.1007/s10825-022-01896-8.

Patel, Ishan et al. (July 2022). "Smart Wheelchair Management System for disabled people". In: Lecture Notes in Electrical Engineering, pp. 283–294. DOI: 10.1007/978-981-19-1906-0_26.

SKILLS

Full-Stack Development React Js, .NET Core, SQL, NextJs, NodeJs

AI Python, Tensorflow, CNNs, NLP Cloud AWS Certified Developer Associate

Last updated: April 13, 2024